Someone is missing.
Shutter Island is a drama, thriller, mystery film directed by Martin Scorsese.
World War II soldier-turned-U.S.
Marshal Teddy Daniels investigates the disappearance of a patient from a hospital for the criminally
insane, but his efforts are compromised by troubling visions and a mysterious doctor.
Teddy Daniels, played by Leonardo DiCaprio.
Chuck Aule, played by Mark Ruffalo.
Dr. Cawley, played by Ben Kingsley.
Dr. Naehring, played by Max von Sydow.
Dolores, played by Michelle Williams.
Rachel 1, played by Emily Mortimer.
Shutter Island is a 2010 American neo-noir psychological
thriller film directed by Martin Scorsese.
The screenplay was adapted by Laeta Kalogridis from the
2003 novel of the same name by Dennis Lehane.
It follows Deputy U.S.
Marshal Edward "Teddy" Daniels and his partner Chuck, who come to the fictional Shutter Island in Boston Harbor to investigate its
criminal psychiatric facility after one of its patients goes missing; Daniels has his own ulterior motives for taking the case.
The film stars Leonardo DiCaprio and Mark Ruffalo, with Ben Kingsley,
Max von Sydow and Michelle Williams in supporting roles.
Development began when Phoenix Pictures acquired the film rights to the novel directly from
Lehane after Columbia Pictures had allowed their rights to lapse in 2003.
Phoenix hired Laeta Kalogridis to work on a screenplay for a year, and in 2007
announced that Scorsese and DiCaprio had both joined the project.
Production began on March 6, 2008, at various locations in Massachusetts – Long Island, while not used as a location, was the inspiration for the fictional island –
including Peddocks Island (as the island), East Point (as the lighthouse), and the Medfield State Hospital (as the facility); filming ended on July 2, 2008.
Partnering with Paramount Pictures, the film had its wide release on February
19, 2010, and received generally positive reviews from critics.
It was chosen by the National Board of Review as one of the top ten
films of 2010, and grossed $295 million worldwide.
The film is also noted for its soundtrack, which prominently used classical music, such as that of Gustav
Mahler, Krzysztof Penderecki, György Ligeti, John Cage, Ingram Marshall, and Max Richter.
In 2025, the film was voted for the "Readers' Choice" edition of The New York Times' list
of "The 100 Best Movies of the 21st Century," finishing at number 169.
The film explores themes of island, based on novel or
book, hurricane, investigation, u.s. marshal.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.